黄昏双镖客
当生命毫无价值时  死亡就有它的报酬
"where life had no value, death,sometimes, had its price.
因此赚赏金的杀手出现了
that is why the bounty killers appeared."
圣经
车票  车票
tickets.
请拿出车票
tickets, please.
车票
tickets.
谢谢  车票
thank you. tickets.
这里去图冠卡里远吗?
Is it far to tucumcari?
三  四分钟后就经过那里
we should pass there in about three or four minutes.
谢谢
thanks.
对不起  但牧师你弄错了
excuse me, but you've made a mistake, reverend.
我无意听到你说要去图冠卡里
I couldn't help hearing you're going to tucumcari.
我在那里卖货的  我可以告诉你  你上错车了
I peddle goods around here, and I better tell you you're on the wrong train.
最近图冠卡里的是阿马里路站
I think the nearest stop to tucumcari is amarillo.
在圣菲下车  沿阿马里路回去...
by getting off at sante fe and returning by way of amarillo...
就可以去到你的目的地
you should be able to get right where you're going.
这火车不在图冠卡里停站的
you see, the train doesn't stop at tucumcari.
它会在那里停站
this train'll stop at tucumcari.
大家都别紧张!
take it easy, everybody!.
你为何停下来?  有问题吗?
why'd you stop? something gone wrong?
有人拉了紧急掣
somebody pulled the emergency cord.
你不可以随意拉紧急掣下车的
hey, mister, you just can't pull the emergency cord and jump off.
你为何弄停火车?  若你想下车  就...
why'd you stop that train? If you want to get off, you...
如果有乘客想下车  铁路公司...
well, the railroad company'd be mighty pleased to make any arrangements...
会乐意安排的
for any passenger if you want to get off here, sir.
我已经下车了  谢谢
I did get off. thanks.
好  开车吧  走
all right, let's go!. go ahead!
通缉: 谋杀犯高佳尔
赏金: 十万元
高佳尔亲自在上面  加了两个"零"字
guy passed by here in person and added on those two zeros.
他看见这么少的赏金  非常不高兴
he was spittin' mad when he saw what they was offerin'. he wasn't flattered.
他说: 只悬赏一千元抓我  太少了
he said, "a measly thousand bucks for me is much too little.
我值更多钱
I'm worth a lot more than that."
然后他就自己加多两个"零"
he said that, and then he added the zeros on the thousand.
没有人胆敢面对这个杀人犯吧?
there isn't anyone got the guts to face that killer, eh?
起码...
at least...
至今还是这样
it's been that way till now.
他在哪?
where is he?
我不知道他今天在哪
I have no idea where he'd be today.
-别动  -但是  高佳尔...
- hold still. - but guy...
-我说别动  -别伤害我
- hold still, I said. - you hurt me with those hands of yours.
-照我的话做  -别这样!
- then do as I tell ya. - stop it!
看  你令我丢了肥皂
now see, you've made me drop the soap.
-慢着  我拿给你  -你气死我了
- wait, I'll get it for ya. - you're killing me.
看  那是什么?
oh, look. what's that?
对不起  小姐
pardon me, ma'am.
我宰了你
I'll kill you for this.
你的赏金  1000美元
there you are. a thousand dollars.
通缉: 卡比比红仔  赏金二千元
卡的事  你知道多少?
what do you know about Cavanagh?
约一个星期前  他在白石镇出现过
about a week ago he was seen at white rocks.
谢谢
thanks.
若你有兴趣...
If it's of any interest to ya...
有人来这里问过他的事
somebody else dropped in to see me about him.
谁?
who?
我没有见过他
I'd never seen him before.
他名叫蒙哥
his name is monco.
白石镇
有火吗?
Iight?
你认识卡比比吗?
you know baby Cavanagh?
告诉我  哪里可以找到他?
now tell me, you know where I can find him?
在那一张桌子
there, at that table.
他背向着你
he's got his back to ya.
谢谢
thanks.
换两张牌
two cards.
赌注是什么?
didn't hear what the bet was.
赌你的生命
your life.
生或死  你来决定
alive or dead... it's your choice.
放了红仔
Iet red go.
二千元不是个小数目
two thousand dollars. It's a lot of money.
我要三年才赚得到
takes me three years to earn it.
做警长的  不是应该勇敢  忠心...
tell me, isn't a sheriff supposed to be courageous, loyal...
还必须老实吗?
and above all, honest?
对  他是这样
yeah, that he is.
我想你们需要换警长
I think you people need a new sheriff.
修伊
Hughie.
尼尔  你好吗?
how are you, Nino?
我见到你就更好了
better when I see you.
走吧
go on. go ahead.
打开闸门
open it.
-什么事?  是谁?  -是罗特  先生
- what's up? who is it? - Rodriguez, senor.
你跟我们来
you. come along.
我让你活着  英雄
I'm letting you live, hero.
让你告诉所有人你看见些什么
that's so you can tell everybody you've seen what takes place here.
悬红一万元
缉拿印迪奥  不管生或死
就为了那些钱
for the lousy money.
你拿了赏金  让我坐牢
you took money to put me behind bars.
你早该趁机杀了我
you should've killed me when you could.
对你会有好处的
It would be better for you.
对他们也是
and for them.
孩子多大了?
how old's the boy?
我问孩子多大了?
how old is the boy, I asked?
他十八个月大
he's 18 months now.
刚好我坐牢那么久
just the time that I was in jail.
你拿了那笔赏金...
you used the reward that you got...
成家立室
to start raising a family.
所以我觉得你的家我也有一份
and that's why I feel your family is partly mine.
现在我要取回我那一份
I'll take my part now.
出去
outside.
他们都是无辜的  求你放了他们!  都是我不好
they're both innocent. please let them go! I was the one. you know that.
我知道  我也知道你恨透了我
I know. I'm sure you hate me just enough.
这回你有机会射我了
this time you'll have a chance to shoot me, but not in the back.
放开他
Iet go.
音乐停了就开始
when you hear the music finish, begin.
你猜你行吗?
or do you think you can?
开始吧
Iet's start.
快点
now.
-再点数吧  -是的
- check those figures again. - yes, sir.
你好  先生  午安
good day, sir. good afternoon.
莫蒂默
Mortimer.
-道格拉斯·莫蒂默  -莫先生  弗吉尼亚人吗?
- Douglas Mortimer. - Mortimer. Virginia, isn't it?
-卡罗来纳  -对了  卡罗来纳
- Carolina. - that's right, Carolina.
可以为你效劳吗?
can I help in some way?
-我要找一家一流的银行  -这就是了
- I'm looking for a first-class bank. - oh, but exactly.
是吧
yeah.
境内最大最安全的银行
the largest and most secure bank in the territory.
莫先生  我可以向你保证  我们银行...
well, mr. Mortimer, I want to assure you our bank here...
齐备所有保安设施
has everything... all the safeguards you're looking for.
我相信你  但我的存款数目很大
I don't doubt that, but I have a large sum to deposit.
假设我是个劫匪
now, suppose I'm a bandit.
劫匪?
a bandit?
带着一班杀手的危险人物
a very dangerous bandit with a gang of killers.
我最可能想打劫哪一家银行?
what would be the most impossible bank for me to rob?
你这情况来说  我说只会打劫埃尔帕索银行
In your case, the one bank I would suggest is the bank of el paso.
连印迪奥也不敢打劫他们
not even lndio would dare to attack that one.
它不只是银行  是个要塞
It's not a bank. It's a fortress there.
下一班往埃尔帕索的火车  几点开?
what time's the next train for el paso?
十一点半  我发电报通知埃尔帕索...
11:30. I'll telegraph to my colleague...
的同事  说你会去那里
in the bank of el paso that you're going to arrive.
谢谢
thanks.
埃尔帕索
先生  长官  上将  欢迎
hey, mister. captain. general. welcome.
要找马厩或房间吗?  要洗个澡吗?
do you need a stable or a room? do you want to take a bath?
我是弗兰  马厩在这里
my name is fernando. the stable is right here.
那是你的酒店
and that is your hotel.
为何指定这一家酒店?
why this hotel and not some other?
你不会喜欢另外那一间
you probably wouldn't like that other place as much, senor.
那里蟑螂到处跑的
you'd have to spend half the night shootin' cockroaches.
这里价钱便宜得多
at this hotel, the rooms will cost you so much less.
还有一个女主人
and there's a landlady at this one, senor.
-结了婚的吗?  -是的  但她不在乎
- married? - yes, but she doesn't care.
那是银行  我一赚到钱就放进去
that's the bank. as soon as I get some money, I'll put it in.
你得先赚点钱
well, you're gonna have to earn it first.
我可以给你五角钱  只要你...
I have 50 cents here for you if you'll let me know...
一见到陌生人来  你就通知我
when anybody you've never seen before here in el paso comes to town.
酒店那边刚有陌生人出来
at the hotel, senor. a stranger just came outta there.
他住在哪?
where's he staying?
那一间酒店
the hotel.
见到别的陌生人就告诉我
Iet me know if you see any more strangers.
好的
sure, senor.
-有何贵干?  -我要这上面的房间
- help you, sir? - I want the room right above.
抱歉  出租了  没办法
I'm sorry, it's occupied. It's too bad.
酒店已经爆满  很抱歉
the hotel's filled to capacity. I'm sorry.
你想要我们最好的房子  但它经常住了人
the room you want is our best. It's always occupied.
谁住在那里?
by who?
看登记册吧
check the register.
玛莉!
mary!
是马先生
It's senor martinez.
-它现在无人住  -有人住的!
- It's free now. - that room is taken!
我去看看
I'll see to it.
他只是个可恶的野蛮鬼!
he's nothing but a wild, vicious animal!
还很高呢  不是吗?
he's tall, isn't he?
你真淫荡!
you're just dirty!
老板  快  结帐!
proprietor, quick! my bill!
给我算帐!
I want my bill!
-结帐  -你不用迁出
- before he comes down, give me my bill. - there's no need to check out.
没事的  我给你换房
everything's gonna be all right. I'll give you another room immediately.
最好的房间  新婚套房吧
It's the best in the whole hotel. we'll let him have the bridal suite.
结帐!  我想留下  但不行
no, mary, the bill. I'd like to stay, only I can't.
-别走!  -我要应约...
- don't go, mr. martinez. - I have an appointment elsewhere.
老马!
martinez
先生  你想怎样?
yes, senor, what do you want?
我不穿的
I don't wear 'em.
你想起我  真是我的荣幸  谢谢
I'm honored that you thought of me. thank you.
看着这个
watch this.
你们好
hello, my friends.
你好  印迪奥
hello, lndio.
我真的马上就赶来
you see, I didn't waste a minute coming here.
老印一找我  我必马上来
Indio calls and groggy comes running right away.
山佐呢?
and Sancho?
若你要等山佐  我四年后再回来
If you're waiting for Sancho, I'll go and come back in about four years.
他入狱了  坐四年监
he's in prison for four years.
无女人  无钱  无阳光
no women, no dollars, no sun.
他真可怜  但我们都还好
bad for him. not so bad for the rest of us.
被抓了的人不值得人尊重?
a man who gets caught doesn't deserve respect, huh?
怎么回事?
what's it all about, huh?
你听着
now just listen.
埃尔帕索的银行
a bank at el paso.
想一想吧
Iet's see.
当这里是银行里面  尼尔就是保险箱
we'll say this is the inside of the bank. Nino is the safe.
它重三吨  不能用炸药打开
which weighs three tons and can't be opened with dynamite.
那边有两个出纳员
there's the part with two cashiers.
那是经理的桌子
this is the manager's desk.
后面是一个装着酒瓶的  漂亮柜子...
right in back is a fancy cabinet containing bottles...
可以招待一些富有存户
for offering drinks to the rich depositors.
那边是大门  他们在对面建了双层墙壁
there's the main door, and opposite they built a double wall.
那会怎么样  高基?
what happens, groggy?
假设你已经  把出纳员和经理干掉
Iet's say you've already killed the two cashiers and the manager.
接着数分钟内  你控制了银行
for the next few minutes, you're the boss of the bank.
怎么样?
now what?
时间浪费了
the time's been wasted.
对  浪费了  尤其是如果要...
right, a waste of time. especially, groggy, to blast open...
炸开保险箱  要用许多炸药...
that damn iron safe, we'd have to be using so much dynamite...
整间银行也会给夷平
that the whole bank would just disappear.
你们也一并炸死
and you'd all go up with it.
况且  有保险箱也不等于...
besides, the presence of a safe alone doesn't always signify...
里面一定有钱
that there is money inside.
为使你更加明白...
to help you understand what I mean...
我想讲一个故事
I would like to relate a nice little parable.
从前有一个木匠
once upon a time there was a carpenter.
你以为木匠赚不到钱吧?
you don't think a carpenter can make money, eh?
是吗?  你错了
no? you're wrong.
这个人风生水起  因为他是造保险箱的
this one did well because he was a builder of safes.
以前有个银行家...
there was a banker once...
决定要掩饰他的铁装保险箱...
who decided he must have his iron safe disguised...
使它看似木柜
to look like a wood cabinet.
为了造好它...
to get it made...
他找那个木匠  但一天...
the banker goes to our carpenter for the job, and one day...
在天意的安排下...
as destiny has it...
木匠去到埃尔帕索
the carpenter's in el paso.
他碰巧走进银行  他发现到什么?
he happens to walk into the bank there, and what does he find?
那个柜子
the cabinet.
因为木柜是他造的  他马上就认出它
since he'd worked on the cabinet, he spotted it right away.
那天开始  他不能再工作了
from that day on, he couldn't work anymore.
很可惜  因为...
pity, because...
他还有别的事要做
there was something he had to do.
他有个奇想
there was this crazy idea.
一直在他脑海...
and it stayed...
不磨不灭...
他想插手里面的钱
to put his hands on the money inside.
走进银行去抢掉那些钱
get in there and grab all the money.
你定以为那个木匠  一定很幸运...
sure, you think that carpenter was lucky the way things work out...
一切顺利  走进银行去
that he was lucky to go in just that bank.
但事实不如此
It wasn't true.
他的好运从那天开始到头了
his good fortune stopped that day.
因为后来...
because later...
他坐监的时候...
as a prisoner...
碰上了我
he ran into me.
木匠把故事告诉我  我告诉了你们
the carpenter told me the story, and I tell you.
钱不在保险箱内  在这里!
the money isn't in the safe. It's right in this!
约一百万
almost a million dollars in it.
你在图冠卡里的同事告诉我  这银行...
your colleague in tucumcari told me that this bank...
的存款量是本州之冠
has the largest deposits in the whole state.
对  莫先生
yes, that's correct, mr. Mortimer.
我们手上有五十万的储备
here at the bank at el paso we have half a million dollars in reserve on hand.
知道了  你肯定这银行够安全吗?
I see. you sure this bank is secure enough to hold that much?
你一把钱存进这家银行...
from the moment your money's on deposit here...
就可以安枕无忧
you can sleep without any worries.
况且...
besides...
银行关门之后  有持械守卫驻守的...
when the bank is closed, an armed guard always remains here...
外面还有巡逻队当值
and a patrol is on guard outside.
连三藩市银行  保安也没那么严密
even the bank of san francisco isn't that well protected.
对  其实...
exactly. the truth is...
想打劫我们  真是妙想天开...
to try robbing us would be so futile...
大笨蛋才会这样想
that only a complete fool would attempt it.
对
yeah.
或者疯汉子吧
or a complete madman.
滚开  别挡路!
get out of the way! get out of here!
新消息
more news, amigo.
又有陌生人吗?
another stranger in town?
对  我还知道别的事
yes. and I know something else.
我没告诉你还有另一个陌生人
there was another stranger I didn't tell you about.
听着  你这臭小子!
Iisten to me, you sawed-off little runt!
我要知道共有多少人
I want to know how many men there are all together.
本来有两个  现在多了两个
well, there were two. now there's two more.
在哪里?
where?
在酒吧
In the saloon.
威士忌
whiskey.
先生  你干嘛来我这里找死?
Iisten, mister, why do you choose my place to commit suicide?
我认识那个人  你活过来真是奇迹
I know that man. It's a miracle you're alive.
怎么拿着枪的人  也愿意受侮辱?
why should a man walk around with a pistol and let himself be insulted?
真是非常奇怪
It's mighty strange.
若那驼子不杀你...
If the hunchback didn't shoot you...
他一定有非常重要的理由
he had a very important reason, that's all.
我也这么想
I was thinking that myself.
一  二...
1, 2...
三  四  五...
3, now 4, now 5...
六  七  八  九  十...
6, 7, 8, 9, 10...
十一  十二  十三...
11, 12, 13...
十四  十五  十六...
14, 15, 16...
十七  十八  十九...
17, 18, 19...
二十  二十一  二十二...
20, 21, 22...
二十三  二十四...
23, 24...
二十五  二十六...
25, 26...
二十七  二十八  二十九...
27, 28, 29...
三十  三十一...
30, 31...
三十二  三十三...
32 and 33.
马氏兄弟被杀手夺命
不要  不
no, no.
好了  起来
all right, now.
我不认识他!
I don't know him!
不要这样  你认识他
come on, now, you know everybody.
我谁也不认识  我死了!  明白吗?
I don't know anybody anymore! I'm dead! understand?
我以前曾经谁都认识
well, there was a time when I knew everybody.
很久以前了  这里本来还未开发
that was a long time ago when all this was prairie.
现在人人都那么匆忙...
In these days everybody's in a hurry. that's right...
还有那些一无是处的火车!
with your damned good-for-nothing trains!
真呕心!
disgusting!
一天  铁路公司有人来找我
one day, someone from the railroad comes here to see me.
他说  "先知  铁路将会路经你这房子"
he says, "prophet, the railway's gonna go right past your house."
我说: "是吗?  "
"ls that so?" I said.
他说: "对了"
"yep, that right," he says.
"所有火车都会路经这里"
"all those trains gonna go right past here.
"最好把你的地卖给铁路公司吧"
the best thing for you, prophet, is sell your land to the company...
"否则我们就买姓贝的"
or else we'll buy baker's.
"他住在隔壁  我把路轨装在这里"
he lives next to your place, and I'll put the tracks here...
"一定吵得你发疯"
and that'll make you go crazy.
"你愿意卖地给我们?  "
will you sell out to our company, prophet?"
我说: "是吗?  "
"oh, is that so?" says l.
他很焦急  想我卖地
he was very anxious for me to sell out.
你猜我怎对他说?
you know what I told him about the railroad?
你猜我对他筑铁路有何建议?
you know what I told him he could do with his railroad?
你猜我决定如何?
you know what my decision about selling was?
你拒绝他
well, you said no.
对了  拒绝他  和他那些鬼火车!
you're right about that. no to him and his damn trains!
怎么也不卖!
I wouldn't! no!
听着  老伯
Iook, listen to me, old man.
你应该是一个先知
you're supposed to be a prophet.
我不要听你谈什么火车
I didn't come here to listen to you rattle on about trains.
我想知道这个人的事  但你什么都不知道
I want to find out about this man. It's obvious you don't know anything.
别批评我  若你只为此而来...
no need to be insulting. If that's all you came here to do...
趁我还没发脾气  你马上走
you can clear out of my house fast before I lose my temper.
明白吗?
understand?
你去哪?
hey! where you goin'?
还是趁你没有发脾气  我先走了
I guess I better leave before you go and lose your temper.
你怎么了?  你干嘛那么笨?
what's the matter with you? why are you so dang stupid?
快拿枪给我
hurry up, give me that pistol there.
就在你后面
yeah, right there behind ya.
快!
hurry!
就是那个  拿过来
yes, that's the one. now, hand it over.
对了  把枪给我  你问及的人
that's it. give me that gun. the man you asked about.
只有一个问题: 他怎带枪的?
there's only one question: how does he carry his gun?
戴在这里  在肚子前面?
he wears it here, across his belly?
你怎不一早告诉我?
well, why didn't you tell me that in the first place, my boy.
我认识你想查的那个人
of course I know the man you're trying to find out about.
我当然认识他
of course I know him.
他是莫蒂默上校
he's colonel Douglas Mortimer.
莫蒂默  好英勇的军人
Mortimer... a brave man, a soldier.
他是卡罗来纳的神枪手
he was known as the best shot in the Carolinas.
很好的军人
a great soldier.
他已经像你一样  是赚赏金的杀手
now he's reduced to being a bounty killer, same as you.
就是因为火车!
because of trains!
就是那些可恶  该死的火车!
because of the damn trains! damn 'em!
拿它到车站  这位先生要走了
take it to the station. the gentleman's leavin'.
慢着
hold it.
拿回来
take it back.
拿到车站去
take it to the station.
-进去  -车站!
- go inside. - the station!
像我们耍的把戏一样
just like the games we know.
-他拾起它了  -或者是个把戏
- he's picking it up. - a trick, maybe.
干这一行的人  怎可以用这种小玩意?
how can somebody in my business go around with a contraption like this?
那个小玩意...
that contraption...
差点送你归西了
almost sent you to your grave.
你忘了一件事  我是向着你的帽子开枪
you're forgetting one thing, colonel... I was shooting at your hat.
我只是射你的帽子
well, I was only shooting at yours.
但好像我先开枪
but I recall firing first.
小子...
boy...
我年近五十了
I've reached almost 50 years of age with my system.
很少人在这儿活得久
not many men last long in these parts.
你猜你会活多久?
how long do you expect to last?
比他们的时间长得多
much longer than that.
我抓到印迪奥  拿到万元赏金后...
when I get my hands on lndio and that $10,000...
就会买个小地方  退休吧
I'm gonna buy myself a little place, possibly retire.
我认为我们不该再斗
well, I don't believe we ought to start another fight.
但你忘了一件小事
but you forget one small detail.
什么?
what's that?
我也想抓印迪奥
I wanna get my hands on lndio too.
当然  在我得手后
sure, after me.
或在你前头
or before you.
或同一时间
or at the same time.
这算是个建议吗?
Is that a proposition?
平等的拍档关系
an equal partnership.
为什么跟你拍档?
why? why should l?
有三个理由
I can think of three reasons.
首先  他们有十四个人
first is there's 14 of them.
人数不少
yeah, that's a lot.
对于我来说  很多
a lot for me.
两个人合力也未必可以
yeah. no small number even for two of us.
第二个原因呢?
second reason?
第二个原因...
second reason...
第二个原因是  你可能要以一敌十五
the second reason is you could make it 15 to one.
别忘了我也想参与这游戏
don't forget I wanna play in this game too.
你也知道两个猎人  追一个猎物...
as you're aware, when two hunters go after the same prey...
结果只会自相残杀  我们不想这样
they usually end up shooting each other in the back, and we don't want that.
那上校就要死?
then the colonel dies, hmm?
好了  我慷慨一点
all right, I'll be generous.
你拿了印迪奥的赏金...
you can have the reward for lndio...
我拿其他人的赏金  如何?
and I'll take the reward for the rest of the band.
不行...
No
绝对错了
all wrong.
印迪奥值一万元  其他人的加起来更多
Indio's worth $10,000 dollars, but the rest adds up to much more than that.
黑仔值四千  野人值三千  尼尔二千
blackie's worth four, wild's worth three, Nino two.
尼尔一千
Nino's one.
费高二千
well, frisco's worth two.
那就是一万
that's ten thousand.
对  但是...
yeah, but...
一定还有别人  算起来会有更多钱
there's a few more that'll add up to more than that, I'm sure.
-你怎知道?  -我消息灵通
- how do you know that? - I have my information.
要说的都说了...
when all's said and done...
我还是接受你的建议吧
I think I might just take you up on your proposition.
为这对拍档干杯
Iet's drink to this partnership.
为这拍档干杯  当然不耍把戏
to the partnership, with no tricks, of course.
不耍把戏
no tricks.
那么...
now, then...
我们得设法在途中下手
you realize we're gonna have to figure out some way to get them in the middle.
只可以里应外合  别无他法
one from the outside, one from the inside. there's no other way.
我们其中一个要加入印迪奥的团伙中
one of us will have to join lndio's band.
你说"其中一个"时  干嘛看着我?
why are you looking at me when you say "one of us"?
因为他们不认识你
because they don't know you.
野人一见到我就会动怒
wild sees me and his hump will catch on fire.
告诉我...
tell me...
我该如何加入印迪奥一伙?
how do you propose that l join up with lndio?
或者带玫瑰给他吧?
maybe bring him a bunch of roses?
你可以这样做  但你还是带着贝山佐
you could do that, but I'd suggest you take him Sancho Perez.
谁是贝山佐?
who's Sancho Perez?
印迪奥的朋友  他在闲着
a friend of lndio's. right now he's cooling off.
他在何拉莫监狱闲着
he's cooling off in alamogourdo jail.
你怎么知道?
how do you know all this?
我也有消息来源的
I've got my information too.
很自然  你得安排他出狱
naturally, you'll have to arrange for his, uh, release.
对
naturally.
告诉我...
tell me...
你曾经年轻吗?
were you ever young?
曾经像你一样鲁莽
and just as reckless as you.
某天发生了一件事
then one day something happened.
令我觉得生命可贵
made life very precious to me.
什么事?
what's that?
这问题轻率吗?
or is the question indiscreet?
绝不轻率
the question isn't indiscreet.
但答案可能是
but the answer could be.
他们说你要坐监  坐四年
they told me you were put away. you'd be resting for four long years in prison.
不  只是四星期罢了
no, lndio, for four weeks. no more than four weeks.
那个是什么人?
who is that with you?
他救我出来的  是我的朋友
he got me out. the man's a friend of mine.
他干嘛帮你?  你有问他吗?
why did he help you? did you ask him that?
朋友  你为什么救我出来?
yeah. amigo, why did you help me out?
通缉你们的赏金数目可不少...
well, there's such a big reward being offered on all you gentlemen...
我只想跟着你们  干下一次的买卖
that I thought I might just tag along on your next robbery.
或者把你们送治
I might just turn you into the law.
朋友...
amigo...
这一个答案可以证明你可靠
that's the one answer that would prove you're all right.
你来得刚好  计划已经落实
and you arrived just in time too. the job is already set.
是明天
It's tomorrow.
地点是...
the place is...
埃尔帕索的银行
the bank in el paso.
离埃尔帕索不远有个镇  圣克鲁斯
not far from el paso there's a little town, santa cruz.
明天  黑仔  支哥  柏高...
tomorrow, blackie, chico, paco...
还有你...
and you, amigo...
往圣克鲁斯打劫银行
will rob the bank in santa cruz.
开枪  杀人  把区内的枪都抢掉...
shoot, kill, get every gun in the area after you...
特别是埃尔帕索那些
especially those from el paso.
我们去处理其余的
any others around, we'll take care of them.
完成后  大家在拉斯波马拉见
and then after the job, we'll all meet again at las palmeras.
你去哪?
where are you going?
如果要开枪...
well, if there's gonna be any shooting...
我得休息一下
I gotta get my rest.
你昨天讲那个故事时  我信以为真
hey, amigo, you know when you told that story yesterday, I fell for it.
大笑话  对吗?
big joke, wasn't it, amigo?
谁说我在说笑?
who said I was jokin'?
我不明白  若那是真的...
I don't get that. If it's true...
可惜你要死
too bad you have to die.
什么事?
what is it?
他们该到了圣克鲁斯
by now they should be at santa cruz.
你听着...
Iisten, shorty...
印迪奥和他的同党  刚打劫了这里的银行
Indio and his band have just robbed the bank here in town.
你坐下来  向埃尔帕索那边发警号...
now why don't you just sit down and send out the alarm to el paso...
还有  警告附近的城镇
and the rest of the towns around here and warn 'em, right?
但我没听到银行有枪声  我该听到的
but, mister, I didn't hear any shots at the bank, and I sure would have.
你或可以听到一枪
you might hear one.
发警报
the alarm.
别紧张
easynow.
他们打劫了圣克鲁斯的银行!
they'verobbedthebank atsantacruz!
跟我来!
followme!
高基  电报电缆
groggy, thetelegraph wires.
-再见  先生  -先生  再见
-good day, gentlemen. -good day, sir.
-先生  -午安
- sir. - good afternoon.
另外一边
the other side.
十一...
eleven...
十二...
twelve...
十四...
fourteen...
走吧
Iet's go!
你在干嘛?  你不是要逃走吧?
what are you doin' here? you're not runnin' away, are you?
我不要逃走
no, I'm not running away.
我要追他们  要自己去  我们拆伙了
I'm going after them and I'm going alone. our partnership is dissolved.
等一等  商量一下吧
boy, let's wait and talk it over.
我们只管空谈  没结果我也没埋怨过
all we've done is talk. I've been reasonable with no results.
我们只知道  他圣克鲁斯那部分的计划
now take it easy. we only knew the santa cruz part of this plan.
是你算出他们的策略的
you were the one who had their strategy all worked out.
-我要去见印迪奥  -那我也同来
- now I'm gonna meet lndio. - I see. I better go along.
我自己去...一个人去
I'm going alone... me.
我跟印迪奥有约  谁也不能干涉我
I have an appointment with lndio and I'm not gonna let anyone interfere.
-你肯定吗?  -是的
- you certain about that? - that's right.
那就很抱歉了
In that case I'm sorry.
这不算太糟  印迪奥派了四个人去圣克鲁斯
that's not bad. Indio sent four men to santa cruz.
一个人回来  丝毫无损
and one man returns... a new man without a scratch.
印迪奥不是个傻瓜
mm-mm. Indio's no idiot.
若你上前让他看那伤痕  他或会相信你
when you ride up to him and show him that little nick, he might believe you.
别忘了  从今天起...
and don't forget, that as of today...
这一帮人值四万多元了
the whole gang's worth $40,000 more.
那是银行悬红缉拿他们  的那笔钱
that's the reward offered by the bank to get the money back.
-拍档又合作了吗?  -你怎么想?
- Is the partnership operating again? - just how do you figure?
尝试说服印迪奥往北面走  然后沿着里奥布拉窝走
try to convince lndio to go north, and then go along the rio bravo.
那里最适合突袭  我们可以合力抓到他
It's a good spot for an ambush and we can get him between two fires.
我们里应外合  对吗?
you on the outside, me on the inside, right?
北面吗?
north?
北面
north.
尼尔
hughie.
慢着  我们需要时间打开它  这地方不适合
wait a minute. we need time to open it and this isn't the right place.
其他人呢?
and the others?
-死了?  -对
- dead? - Yeah
往圣克鲁斯之后  我们往埃尔帕索走  受到突袭
after santa cruz, we headed for el paso and they hit us from all sides.
你只能自保  对吗?  你这...
and you just saved your own skin, isn't that right, you yellow...
你已完成责任  走吧
you did your part of it. Iet's go.
我们往哪里去?
which way we headed?
北面
north.
北面?  沿着里奥布拉窝?
north? along rio bravo canyon?
有何不可?
why not?
那里最容易受突袭
seems like a good place for an ambush to me.
还有更好的建议吗?
you know a better way to go?
对  南面
yeah, south.
往边界走?
ride to the border?
他们没预期你会过境  因为他们已发了警报
they'll never expect you to cross the border now that the alarm's been sent.
还是往东走
think we'll head east.
我知道有一个地方  阿加卡兰特
there's a place I know about, agua caliente.
这就是阿加卡兰特
here we are. that's agua caliente.
我在那里有朋友
yes, I have many friends here.
像个停尸间一样
It looks just like a morgue.
不过小心点
but look out.
它有可能变成停尸房
It could be one so easily.
-他们抗拒陌生人  -他们谁都不喜欢
- they don't like strangers. - no, they don't like anybody.
野人  你没见过这位朋友的枪法吧?
wild, you never saw our friend here shoot, right?
你们呢?
did any of you?
我们不知道  你遇上危急情况会怎样
we don't know how you'd be in emergencies.
我在想  这地方很适合
I was thinking, this is the right place.
我有个方法  让你显身手
I got a way you can show the men.
怎么样?
how's that?
你自己一人走进城去
go into town alone, amigo.
好棒
bravo.
可否说你怎到这里来?
do you mind tellin' me how you got here?
只是分析出来的
I just reasoned it out.
我猜你会告诉印迪奥...
I figured you'd tell lndio...
走的方向  刚巧是我们说好的相反...
to do just exactly the opposite of what we agreed...
他疑心重  于是走另一个方向
and he's suspicious enough to figure out somethin' else.
既然埃尔帕索不是在考虑之列  所以我就来了
since el paso was out of the question, well, here I am.
甜酒  要双份
rum... a double.
大家都饮特奎拉酒
tequila for all of us.
这不是抽烟的朋友吗?
If it isn't the smoker.
记得我吗  朋友?
remember me, amigo?
当然吧...在埃尔帕索
of course you do. el paso.
世界真小
It's a small world.
对  而且还真糟
yes, and very, very bad.
来吧  你又该点火了
now, come on. you light another match.
我通常吃完饭才吸烟  十分钟后回来
I generally smoke just after I eat. come back in ten minutes.
十分钟后你已死了  起来!
ten minutes you'll be smoking in hell. get up!
冷静一点
stay calm.
站起来
on your feet.
古罗
cucillo.
数三声
count to three.
一...
one...
二...
two...
三!
three!
住手!
stop it!
你是谁?
who are you?
能够为你打开保险箱的人
I'm the one who can open the safe for you.
什么保险箱?
what safe, senor?
埃尔帕索那个  你比我早一步
the one from el paso. you got there ahead of me.
-不过...  -不过?
- however... - however?
若你打开保险箱  就会毁掉一半银纸
open that safe and you're gonna destroy half the bank notes.
我可以不用炸药弄开它
I can open it without blowing it up.
要多少钱?
what'll it cost?
五千元
five thousand.
我只付二千
two's all I'll pay you.
五千
five.
别碰!
keep your hands off it!
偷钱倒容易  最难保存的是赃款
It's easy to steal. the trouble is in keeping the loot.
拿它出来
take it out.
现在新墨西哥  人人都在追捕我们
now every man in new mexico is after us.
若发现我们跟手上的钱  我们就必死无疑
If they catch one of us with money we'll all end up the same way.
若我认为有必要  我们就得等一个月
we're going to wait here for an entire month if I think it's necessary.
然后才分赃
then everybody will get his share.
你也要等一个月才拿到钱
and you will wait a month to get your money.
这个当然
naturally.
我在小旅馆内
I'll be in the tavern.
周围的空气跟食物一样很糟糕
the air around here stinks anyway, just like the food.
但一个月很快就会过去
but the month will go fast.
就在这里
right here.
走吧
Iet's go.
我很担心你
I was worried about you.
自己一个人  有那么多难题处理
all alone with, uh, so many problems to solve.
全都在这儿
It's all right here.
去吧
go ahead.
你不该把苹果射下来的
you shouldn't have shot the apples off that tree.
戴着它
put it on.
那个埃尔帕索的警长在干嘛?
what's he doing now, this sheriff of el paso?
现在吗?  在找银行失掉的钱
right now? Iookin' for the cash that was in the bank.
对
right.
假若他在埃尔帕索镇外  找到这两个人的尸体...
and suppose he finds the bodies of these men just outside el paso...
身上又有很多钱?
with lots of money on them?
警长会怎样想?
what will the sheriff think?
他会...
well, he...
对了
that's right.
斯利姆
slim.
什么事  尼尔?
what is it, Nino?
计划改变了
a change of plans.
印迪奥  想要你...
Indio wants you to...
无子弹的
It's not loaded.
你们该快走了
I think you should get out fast now.
你的枪也无子弹
here's your guns without bullets.
别让印迪奥在附近找到你们
Iisten. don't you let lndio find you both around.
我知道你不喜欢问题  但你为何这样做?
I know you don't like questions, but why are you doing this?
你知道蒙哥是赏金猎人有多久了?
how long have you known that monco's a bounty killer?
今晚才知道的  怎么了?
I found out tonight. why?
他一到  我就知道他是了
I knew he was one from the first moment he arrived.
另外那个也是赚赏金的
the other one's also a bounty killer.
所以我有个主意
so I have an idea.
他们有利用价值
they'll be useful to us.
我们试试看
we'll try it.
那两个人  比我们有枪的人身手好
those men are a lot better than mine with a gun.
我们让他们来一次枪战
so we'll let all of them get mixed up in a gun battle.
但那对于我不重要
but that won't really matter to me.
对你也是
or you.
因为我们已远走高飞了  对吗?
because we'll be far away, right?
我们还拿所有钱
and we'll have all the money.
去吧
go on.
去弄醒古罗
go on and wake cucillo.
是谁做的?
who did it?
为何不看看那把刀子?
why don't you look at the knife?
是我的
It's mine.
它不该在此吧?
then it shouldn't be there, should it?
但我没杀他  不是我做的
but I didn't kill him. I didn't do it.
很难证明的
It's difficult to prove that.
印迪奥  我是无辜的
I am innocent.
你的马在外面
one of your horses is outside.
看你能否跑到它那里
Iet's see if you can get to it.
印迪奥?
lndio
他刚杀了瘦子
he just killed slim.
他还帮那两个赏金猎人逃走
and he... he helped those two bounty killers get away.
找他们回来...
I want them back...
现在就去
right now.
马上去
你们在干嘛?
what are you doing here?
去抓他们!
go and get them back!
高基
groggy
那两个赏金猎人威胁着我们  要马上干掉他们
those two bounty killers are sitting on our backs and must be killed right away.
不可以让他们走
we can't let 'em go free.
好了
It's done now.
准备离开这里
prepare to get out of here.
来  尼尔
here.
别动
hold it.
这个主意不错  印迪奥
not a bad idea.
但你忘了我
but I'm one thing you forgot about.
把门打开
open it up now.
好了  快打开它
all right, come on now, open it.
我来应付印迪奥
Ieave lndio to me.
好吧
all right.
到底它在哪里?
where in hell is it?
我要把他们碎尸万段  不过要先取他们的胆出来
I'll kill 'em, but I'll rip out their guts first.
我有个计划
I have a plan.
什么?
what?
我们等吧
Iet's just wait.
他们会回来的
they'll be back here.
这样我们可以互相照应
and this way, there'll be two of us.
他们能回来吗?  你的人或已杀了他们
can they come back here? your men could've killed them.
谁?  他们?
who? they?
肯定吗?  他们没有吗?
are you sure of that? that they haven't?
我的想法不同
I thought something different.
你命人出去尽快把他们干掉
you made the boys ride on out to make sure they're both killed, and fast.
我不像其他人那么笨
I'm not as dumb as the rest of them.
当时根本没办法
there was no help for it.
去吧
go on.
那个手表...
that watch...
我早已经想问你
It's been a long time that I wanted to ask.
我看得出它对你很有意义
I can see that it means a lot to you.
为什么?
why?
印迪奥!
lndio
听我说
Iisten to me!
我是莫上尉!
this is colonel Mortimer!
道格拉斯·莫蒂默!
Douglas Mortimer!
这名字你听过没有?
does the name mean anything to you?
音乐声停了  就拾起你的枪
when the chimes end, pick up your gun.
试一试向我开枪吧
try and shoot me, colonel.
试一试吧
just try.
你真不小心
very careless of you, old man.
试试这一个
try this.
现在开始吧
now we start.
好棒吧
bravo.
好像有点家族的影子
there seems to be a family resemblance.
给你
here.
当然  是兄妹吧
naturally, between brother and sister.
我的枪
my gun.
小子...
my boy...
你富有了
you've become rich.
你是说我们富有了吧
you mean we've become rich, old man.
不  钱归你所有  你应得的
no, it's all for you. I think you deserve it.
那我们的合作呢?
what about our partnership?
下一次吧
maybe next time.
一万  一万二千...
ten thousand, twelve thousand...
一万五千...
fifteen...
一万六千...
sixteen...
一万七千...
seventeen...
二万二千...
twenty-two...
二万七千
twenty-seven.
有问题吗  小子?
any trouble, boy?
没有  老头
no, old man.
我以为计算出了问题
thought I was having trouble with my adding.
现在没事了
It's all right now.